Contact

43 port said street - Suez - Egypt 00201003987478 (Mobile)

www.linkedin.com/in/mohamed-abouelela-5a6ba973 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Communication
Troubleshooting
Relevance

Languages

Arabic

English

French

Mohamed Abouelela

Information Technology Engineer at EGYPTIAN FERTILIZERS CO. S.A.E

Egypt

Summary

Around 6 years of Information Technology experience ,I have taught a variety of programming languages Skills, especially interested in MAXIMO program as a Technical-Functional Specialist and and in Oracle ERP as Oracle ERP administrator, installations, Trainer, Customer support, Troubleshooting, reports developing, Workflow designer, System configuration and Customization and many other function a creative problem-solver and a fire fighter who adapts well to different situations and thrive on challenges to achieve significant results.

Experience

EGYPTIAN FERTILIZERS CO. S.A.E.

Information Technology Engineer
October 2014 - Present (10 years 4 months)

- 1. Developing and customizing reports of MAXIMO as per Users' defined requirements.
- 2. Customizing and configuring MAXIMO application screens & Database.
- 3. Deploying MAXIMO Workflow cycles.
- 4. MAXIMO Application installation and DB administration.
- 5. Preparing and conducting client training courses in Working with MAXIMO and Oracle ERP Applications.
- 6. Support End Users on MAXIMO and Oracle ERP Applications.
- 7. Backup and Clone Oracle ERP and MAXIMO Database.
- 8. Apply Oracle ERP Patches.
- Apply Oracle ERP Migration from Oracle ERP 11i on Windows Server
 2003 to Oracle ERP 12r on Linux Redhat 5.4
- 10. Design Reports on Birt 3.7 Ver. on MAXIMO 7.5 Ver.

Orascom Construction Industries Information Technology Engineer October 2009 - September 2014 (5 years)

- 1. Developing and customizing reports of MAXIMO as per Users' defined requirements.
- 2. Customizing and configuring MAXIMO application screens & Database.
- 3. Deploying MAXIMO Workflow cycles.
- 4. MAXIMO Application installation and DB administration .
- 5. Preparing and conducting client training courses in Working with MAXIMO and Oracle ERP Applications.
- 6. Support End Users on MAXIMO and Oracle ERP Applications.
- 7. Backup and Clone Oracle ERP and MAXIMO Database.
- 8. Apply Oracle ERP Patches.
- Apply Oracle ERP Migration from Oracle ERP 11i on Windows Server
 2003 to Oracle ERP 12r on Linux Redhat 5.4
- 10. Design Reports on Birt 3.7 Ver. on MAXIMO 7.5 Ver.

FuTech Egypt

MAXIMO system Trainee

March 2009 - September 2009 (7 months)

- 1. Customizing and configuring MAXIMO application screens & Database.
- 2. Deploying MAXIMO Workflow cycles.
- 3. MAXIMO Application installation and DB administration .
- 4. Support End Users on MAXIMO application.

Education

Ain Shams University

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science · (2004 - 2008)